Adventure awaits.
Spirit Untamed is a animation, adventure, family film directed by Elaine Bogan.
Lucky Prescott's life is changed forever when she moves from her home in the city
to a small frontier town and befriends a wild mustang named Spirit.
Lucky Prescott (voice), played by Isabela Merced.
Aunt Cora (voice), played by Julianne Moore.
Prudence Granger (voice), played by Marsai Martin.
Abigail Stone (voice), played by Mckenna Grace.
Hendricks (voice), played by Walton Goggins.
Jim Prescott (voice), played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Spirit Untamed is a 2021 American animated Western musical comedy adventure film
directed by Elaine Bogan and written by Aury Wallington and Kristin Hahn.
The second theatrical film of the Spirit franchise, it is a soft reboot of Spirit: Stallion of the
Cimarron (2002) and is based on characters from Netflix spin-off series, Spirit Riding Free.
With the voices of Isabela Merced, Jake Gyllenhaal, Marsai Martin, Mckenna Grace, Julianne Moore, Walton Goggins, and Andre Braugher, the film is about a
young girl named Fortuna "Lucky" Prescott who moves to the small rural community of Miradero, where she meets the titular wild kiger mustang.
As the son of Spirit and Rain from Spirit: Stallion of the Cimarron, she names the horse
"Spirit" after his father, and Lucky immediately begins to bond with him.
The film was announced to be in development in October 2019, and
production was done remotely during the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film was dedicated to the memory of Kelly Asbury, the co-director
of the original Spirit film, who died on June 26, 2020.
Spirit Untamed was theatrically released in the United
States on June 4, 2021, by Universal Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics who deemed the film inferior to the
original and unnecessary, though its animation and humor was praised.
The film underperformed at the box-office, grossing over $42 million worldwide against a budget of $30
million, making it both DreamWorks Animation's cheapest and lowest-grossing film to date.
The film explores themes of horse, mustang, female
protagonist, animals, wild horse.